Finding Aid for Philip A. Hart Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Visual Materials, 10 linear feet
  - Motion Pictures
    - Averill Harriman, Undersecretary of State for Political Affairs and Walt W. Rostow, Chairman of the Policy and Planning Council of the Department of State, undated; [85193-89]
      - Streaming File: 85193-89, flv
    - Senator Albert Gore interviews Senator William Proxmire and Adrian Fischer, Deputy Director of the U.S. Disarmament Agency about political matters, undated; [85193-90]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 00:27:55
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-90, flv
    - Senator Albert Gore interviews Senator Gale McGee, Senator John O. Pastore, Senator William Fulbright, and Senator Paul Monroney, undated; [85193-91]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 00:27:33
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-91, flv
    - Jewish War Veterans, undated; [85193-92]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:35
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-92, flv
    - Wildlife: Sleeping Bear Dunes, undated; [85193-94]; (U. S. Senator from Michigan, 1959-1976, a conscientious supporter of civil rights, consumer protection and environmentalism, Hart served as floor manager of the 1965 civil rights act and 1968 Open Housing Act, introduced legislation to create Sleeping Bear Dunes and Pictured Rock National Lakeshores and sponsored important consumer legislation. (Undated; L3-3-1-3).)
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:03
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-94
    - IRS Data Center, undated; [85193-95]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:28
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-95, flv
    - Tax Reform; Bishop Emrich, undated; [85193-96]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-96, flv
    - Cherry Pie, undated; [85193-97]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:16
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-97, flv
    - Untitled: Royal Oak Township housing, undated; [85193-98]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:16
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-98, flv
    - Urban Problems, undated; [85193-99]
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:16
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
    - Untitled: Nuclear deterrence, undated; [85193-100]
      - Original:, 16mm film, color, pos, mag, 00:01:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-100, flv
    - Consumers, undated; [85193-101]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-101, flv
    - Consumers, undated; [85193-102]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:22
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-102, flv
    - What Kind of Man, undated; [85193-103]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-103, flv
    - What Kind of Man, undated; [85193-104]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:22
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-104, flv
    - Old People, undated; [85193-105]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-105, flv
    - Conservation, undated; [85193-106]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:02
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-106, flv
    - Conservation, undated; [85193-107]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:22
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-107, flv
    - Jobs, undated; [85193-108]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:05
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-108, flv
    - Jobs, undated; [85193-109]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:22
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-109, flv
    - Why Do People: Campaign spot, 1964; [85193-110]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:12
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-110, flv
    - People Like Him, undated; [85193-111]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:23
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-111, flv
    - Press Speaker, undated; [85193-112]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:22
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-112, flv
    - 4-H Reps in Michigan, June 17, 1959; [85193-113]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:04:38
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-113, flv
    - WMSB-TV and Educational TV, undated; [85193-114]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 00:01:03
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-114, flv
    - The Job of a Senator" [1964 campaign], [85193-115]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:16:40
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-115, flv
    - Interview about Senate Anti-Trust and Monopoly activities, Auto repair industry, Consumers, undated; [85193-116]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 00:29:58
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-116, flv
    - Speech to the annual meeting of the League of Women Voters, undated; [85193-117]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:22:02
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-117, flv
    - Senate Anti-Trust and Monopoly Committee and auto repairs, undated; [85193-118]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 00:05:25
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-118, flv
    - Hart discusses various topics, including Detroit Riot, undated; [85193-119]; (Confirmation of the Secretary of Transportation; Michigan cherries; With Senator Edward V. Long discussing electronic spying; Michigan Week; Boy Scouts; Channel 56 and Educational TV; Detroit Riots (1)(2); Lake Michigan and pollution)
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 00:09:48
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-119, flv
    - Hart discusses Government waste and spending, ABM Defense System, Voting responsibilities, undated; [85193-120]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 00:02:42
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-120, flv
    - Federal Aid to Education, 1, May 23, 1961; [85193-125]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:04:05
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-125, flv
    - Opening of Congress, February 18, 1962; [85193-126]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:04:45
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-126, flv
    - Great Lakes Commission for Economic Development, February 20, 1966; [85193-127]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:02
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-127, flv
    - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films
      The Sleeping Bear Dunes Films were small films with their own "Hart Film #". At one point all of the films relating to the Sleeping Bear Dunes and Pictured Rocks park proposals were combined on a single reel and designated Hart Film #129. All discuss the proposed Sleeping Bear Dunes National Lakeshore or Pictured Rock Lakeshore. A few include other subjects as well.
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-1]; (U. S. Senator from Michigan, 1959-1976, a conscientious supporter of civil rights, consumer protection and environmentalism, Hart served as floor manager of the 1965 civil rights act and 1968 Open Housing Act, introduced legislation to create Sleeping Bear Dunes and Pictured Rock National Lakeshores and sponsored important consumer legislation. (Undated 1-13).)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:46
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-1
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-2]; (U. S. Senator from Michigan, 1959-1976, a conscientious supporter of civil rights, consumer protection and environmentalism, Hart served as floor manager of the 1965 civil rights act and 1968 Open Housing Act, introduced legislation to create Sleeping Bear Dunes and Pictured Rock National Lakeshores and sponsored important consumer legislation. (Undated).)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:10:28
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-2
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-3]; (Michigan State University Report on State Parks)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:48
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-3
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-4]; (Pictured Rocks Park Proposal Promo)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:46
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-4
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-5]; (Pictured Rocks Park Proposal, interview with Hart and Congressman Clevenger)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:48
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-5
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-6]; (U. S. Senator from Michigan, 1959-1976, a conscientious supporter of civil rights, consumer protection and environmentalism, Hart served as floor manager of the 1965 civil rights act and 1968 Open Housing Act, introduced legislation to create Sleeping Bear Dunes and Pictured Rock National Lakeshores and sponsored important consumer legislation. (Undated).)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:47
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-6
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-7]; (Sleeping Bear Dunes, Pictured Rocks Park, Northern Michigan Development Council, final segment of interview filmed for television broadcast)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:08:48
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-7
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-8]; (U. S. Senator from Michigan, 1959-1976, a conscientious supporter of civil rights, consumer protection and environmentalism, Hart served as floor manager of the 1965 civil rights act and 1968 Open Housing Act, introduced legislation to create Sleeping Bear Dunes and Pictured Rock National Lakeshores and sponsored important consumer legislation. (Undated).)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:47
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-8
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-9]; (U. S. Senator from Michigan, 1959-1976, a conscientious supporter of civil rights, consumer protection and environmentalism, Hart served as floor manager of the 1965 civil rights act and 1968 Open Housing Act, introduced legislation to create Sleeping Bear Dunes and Pictured Rock National Lakeshores and sponsored important consumer legislation. (Undated).)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:40
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-9
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-10]; (Sleeping Bear Lakeshore Hearings)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:00:53
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-10
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-11]; (U. S. Senator from Michigan, 1959-1976, a conscientious supporter of civil rights, consumer protection and environmentalism, Hart served as floor manager of the 1965 civil rights act and 1968 Open Housing Act, introduced legislation to create Sleeping Bear Dunes and Pictured Rock National Lakeshores and sponsored important consumer legislation. (Undated).)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:23
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-11
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-12]; (Civil rights legislation; discussion, Hart and Sen. Leverett Saltonstall on national parks, Cape Cod seashore and Sleeping Bear)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:12:37
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-12
      - Sleeping Bear Dunes Films, undated; [85193-129-13]; (Michigan National Parks, Picture Rock)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 00:01:55
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
        - Streaming File: 85193-129-13
    - Senator Hart, 1975-01-24; [85193-564]
      - Original:, 2-inch videotape, color, sound, 00:04:36
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-564, flv
    - Senator Hart, November 11, 1973; [85193-684.21]
      - Original:, 2-inch videotape, color, sound, 00:00:53
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-684_21, flv
    - Senator Hart, march 31, 1970; [85193-9868]
      - Original:, 2-inch videotape, color, sound, 00:04:45
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-9868, flv
    - Senator Hart, November 11, 1973; [85193-684.12]
      - Original:, 2-inch videotape, color, sound, 00:00:45
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 4)
      - Streaming File: 85193-684_12, flv